Matthew A. Cottrell

ClassicCottrell.ca

ClassicCottrell@gmail.com

**** 778-232-4629



My name is Matt and I'm a UI/UX designer. I've been in the software industry for 5 years. When I'm not at work, I'm either involved in film production, drawing weird cartoon characters, or reminiscing about my printing days, when I had access to a vinyl plotter, huge screens and endless rolls of paper.



Experience

- 5 years in a start-up environment
- Outgoing & positive personality
- Enthusiastic & dedicated learner
- Adapts easily to new situations & people
- I work well independently, however, I love working in a team environment & brainstorming with my colleagues.

Work History

Tagga - Creative Lead

UX/UI Lead 2016 - present

- User stories, Site mapping, Conception of new platform tools
- Creation of Low Fidelity to High Fidelity designs through wireframes, sketches, design, mockups, prototyping (pencil paper, adobe XD)
- Software theme & branding, element styles (color exploration, fonts, icons)

Lead Design 2011-2016

- Cross Channel Campaign Strategy
- Design & creation of media for campaigns (in-store print design, facebook/ Instagram/twitter social posts, & responsive websites)
- Front End Development and QA for site deployments
- Social Community Creation
- Social posting and storytelling

Intern

2011

- Video production
- Print preparation

C2 Imaging 2000 - 2010

- Sign Maker
- Large Format Digital Print Operator
- Lün Cutter Press Operator
- Saturn 5 Colour Printing Press Assistant

Education and Training

BCIT - New Media Design & Web Development Certificate2010 - 2011Vancouver Film School - Foundation in Film & Design2006 - 2007Langley Fine Arts School - Fine Arts Major2001 - 2004

Skills

UI/UX Design & Coding

- HTML, CSS	
- Foundation, Bootstrap, SASS, LESS	
- Responsive design	••••
- Email template creation	•••00
- Campaign Monitor & MailChimp	
- Facebook Ad Manager	•••00
- Google Adwords	••000
- Adobe Experience design	•••••

Art & Design

- Adobe Creative suite	•••00
- Photoshop	••••
- Illustrator	••••
- InDesign	•••00
- Video Final Cut & After Effects	•••00
- Lighting & Set Design	••000
- Classical 2D Animation	••000
- Stop Motion & Cinemagraphs GIF's	••000

Print & Layout

- Sign maker (layout and quality control)	••••
- 5 color printing process	•••00
- T-shirt printing process	•••00
- Store Front vinyl sign application	•••00
- Zün (digital die-cutting)	•••00
- Prepress knowledge & understanding	•••00